so let's look at how the processor sees
the memory the processor sees what we
call physical memory which is the memory
contained in the actual memory modules
that we bought and put in the system the
amount of that memory sometimes even
lower than four gigabytes it is almost
never four gigabytes per process that we
have in the system because there can be
tens or even hundreds of processes in a
modern operating system and it is never
16 exabytes per process this is how much
memory we need if we have 2 to the 64th
memory locations which is what you would
have with a 64-bit address so if each
process in a 64-bit machine thinks it
has this much memory there is just no
way we can have enough actual memory for
that so we conclude that the amount of
physical memory we have is usually less
than what all the programs can access if
all the programs access all the memory
they possibly can
they will access much much more than the
memory we actually have the addresses
that the processor uses for the physical
memory have a one-to-one mapping to the
bytes or words in the physical memory so
a given address always goes to the same
physical location and the physical
location always has exactly one physical
address